Now lets have a look at a more complex case.
Lets assume we've made couple of commits, exactly same as in the previous issues, but in a "master" branch, instead of "fix".
And we only realize that late, that making these in the main branch was a mistake.
Furtunately enough theres no problem in that. We are going to fix it now.
First lets create a new "fix" branch first on top of the current commit.
Now all we need is to move "master" back here.
So the last commits will only be in the "fix" branch.
And the overall state will be same as we've seen in the previous issues,
when we made commits in the "fix" branch from the very beginning.
Git has several commands that move the branches, each has various features,
which might be helpful depending on the case so that they complete each other well.
We'll learn them during the screencast. Right now lets use the one we know - "git branch".
We can give the commit to it, together with the branch name. Then it will create a branch with the name given pointing to the commit.
Now this command, as you can see, didnt work as we already have the "master" branch.
To circumvent it lets add the "--force" flag or, shortly "-f".
It will make "git branch" to create a branch if it doesn't exist
or, like in our case, move it if it exist.
Let me try.
Error, because "git branch" require us to leave the branch first, before changing it.
Running again...
It worked. The "master" branch is pointing to the previous commit, exactly what we wanted.
Now new commits are only in the fix branch.
As you see, literally, couple of commands: create a branch and move it.
If you changed your mind you can just move it back: "git branch -f". Let "master" point at the same commit as fix.
Note that I've used a branch name, instead of the commit identifier.
Theres nothing special about it. The branch technically cant point to another branch, but to commit.
And the way I've provided this commit, by identifier or via link, doesn't matter.
For the same purpose, instead of "git branch" its often more convenient to use the "git checkout" command.
We've used the "-b" flag already. It allow us to create a branch with the name given on a given commit and switch into it.
And if we use "-B" and there's such a branch already it will move it and then switch to it.
So its same as "git branch" with the "-f" key and calling a "git checkout" after that.
Executing...
Done. The "master" branch was moved and we switched into it. And the commits,
that we mistakently made in the "master" are now in the "fix".
So the result is the same as if we've initially committed to fix.